As we listen to the Lord closing this section of Scripture, Jesus says,
I am the good shepherd. I know my sheep, and my sheep know me.
Just as the Father knows me, I know the Father, and I lay down my life for the sheep.
I have other sheep that are not of the sheep, and I must bring them also.
They too will listen to my voice, and there shall be one flock and one shepherd.
The reason my Father loves me is that I lay down my life only to take it up again.
No one takes it from me, but I lay it down of my own accord.
I have authority to lay it down, and authority to take it up again.
This command I receive from my Father.
The Jews who heard these words were again delighted.
Many of them said, who is demon-possessed in raising mad?
Why listen to him?
But others, these are not the signs of a man possessed by a demon.
Do you be a demon, open the eyes of one born blood?
The word of the Lord.
So, this passage is a little unique in our series.
We've been going through a series of seven signs, miracles, John calls them signs, and seven I am statements.
And in this particular I am statement, it is the only animate I am statement.
Every other one of them, he is kind of a thing.
He is light.
He is bread.
He is way.
He is life.
He is truth.
We're going to be coming up on his vine.
At one point, he just says, I am.
I would love to see in the conversation.
I am love.
I am.
Okay.
So, this is a statement.
I guess I am.
But in this one, Jesus chooses a very common, um, I won't say caricature, um, persona in the ancient world.
And part of the reason that I think it's a little challenging for us, everyone in Israel either would have been a shepherd, been related to a shepherd, or knew a shepherd really well.
They watched the inner workings of a shepherd all the time.
It was common.
It was every day.
I don't know about you, but I have never met a shepherd in the U.S.
And those who do shepherding here don't do anything like Jesus was referring to them.
So, Jesus actually tells three different stories that you and I don't necessarily pick up on because we don't realize that there are different places that are separate in us with their sheep.
And we come to it, and it almost has to be explained to us.
And the reason I think it's challenging is because I think Jesus was choosing a story that needed no explanation.
Jesus was referring to himself as one animate thing, a lie, a person, a character, an archetype, if you will, and said, I'm not.
It reminds me of when I finished a series of, we had a conference in Nepal.
We were in Tokla, about the middle of the country, and we were done, and we would always have evaluations and, you know, teach us what can we do better, what can we do more of, what can we do less of, what works, what didn't work.
And I remember one of the reviewers wrote in there, and many of the illustrations were helpful, but many of them were not.
I just love hearing that when you're done with a conference.
They said, you know, you're a theater and talked about the beach and the ocean and the feeling of waves knocking you over.
And in Nepal as land lost, very few of us have any money to travel anywhere.
We know what an ocean is, but I've never felt sand in my coast.
I've never been knocked over by a wave.
Could you use some more culturally relevant illustrations?
It was fun.
In some ways, Jesus is using an incredibly culturally relevant illustration that doesn't translate as easily for us.
And so, because of that, I'm going to try to do two things for you.
I'm actually going to preach two shorter messages.
One of them, I'm going to teach on what the word is saying here.
On the second one, I'm going to try to do what Jesus was trying to do with his worries.
And let's see if it'll make sense in a little bit there.
Okay.
The Lord is like by saying that tripper passages were also very prolific in the Old Testament.
There are lots of them.
And in all of those passages, God is the shepherd.
His people are the sheep.
There are leaders who are under-shepherds.
God has really high expectations for those under-shepherds, those people that God uses and leads with.
But the sheep are still here.
I don't know if I've ever heard Ryan do this, but I've done, I've talked about, oh, my people.
Oh, no, you're not mine.
You're dogs.
You're his sheep.
I just get very accepted here.
As an under-shepherds.
By the way, if you haven't met me, my name is Matt.
I've been on staff here for a while.
I love talking to people, kids.
So, in this context, the people who were listening to Jesus at the time, first of all, would have been very, very familiar with the concept of shepherd.
Second of all, they would have been very familiar with the idea that God is ultimately our shepherd.
Let me see if I can just walk you through that really quickly.
But that's not it.
Okay, maybe I'll walk you through it.
Can we skip this?
Thank you for not having me go on your mind.
Okay, the good shepherd.
That's great.
Can you guys see that?
It says the good shepherd on your teams and not dismissed.
There we go.
Okay.
Form 20.
Nope.
That's not what I do.
What's that?
Am I pressing the wrong button?
Yeah.
What's the, all those tech people call it, that fast or something, error between chair and computers?
It's a perfect spot.
I mean, you guys looked bad on me because it was really new, wasn't it?
You're just the other way around, by the way, you know?
Okay, it's a vengeance.
The Lord of my shepherd, I shall not be in one.
Familiar passage.
Psalm 70, verse 20.
You led your people like a flock by the hand of Moses and Aaron.
Moses and Aaron, the younger shepherds.
But who led them?
God led them.
God is the shepherd.
When we, when we, your people, the sheep of your pasture, will praise you forever.
From generation to generation, we will recount your praise.
Again, in the psalm, in verse 1, just one psalm later.
Hear us, O shepherd of Israel, you who lead Joseph like a flock.
Psalm 100, know that the Lord is God.
It is He who has made us.
And we are His.
We are His people.
The sheep of His pasture.
This is a theme.
It goes through Isaiah.
It goes through Ezekiel.
It's throughout the whole Old Testament that God is their shepherd.
And they know what a shepherd is.
They are probably related to one.
Or they might be one.
Okay, are you with me?
Oh, did I, like, do overkill on that?
So, here's my question.
Which of those Old Testament passages did Jesus execute in John chapter 10?
Yeah, all of them or none of them.
And there's not such a single one of them.
Now, there's nothing wrong with that, obviously.
But I think that Jesus was using a very common story.
I mean, it actually tells three stories in this 21-verse message.
And we'll walk through those when we get there.
But He does it in a way that He's trying to get not at your intellect, but rather at your emotions.
And, by the way, He's confused, because at the end, what happens?
They're divided.
I mean, some people are saying, He's dealing with the best.
He's a nut.
Why are you on Smith's neck case?
And all of them are saying, No, no, no, no, no, no.
He's from Isaiah.
I mean, this polarized group of people that have responded to such three stories.
Some of you, if you've been here a year, will remember this slide.
Back when we did spiritual stations.
If you want to, I'll give you just a quick research because this will help to make sense of what I'm trying to do here.
We all have preferences in how we approach God and how we conceive of God.
And this works by Erwin Holmes.
Do I sound like a new one?
Okay.
Now, if someone can get in the store and someone offers you a neck, never say no.
So, I don't worry, I don't worry, but they're offering you a neck.
So, on this grid, by the way, you guys made me sound good.
You turned the microphone down while I jammed.
That was impressive.
Well done.
Since you did that, I won't push the back button again.
I'll try to get it right.
Okay.
Audio illustration later in message.
Oh, yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
Let's go.
You do know that abusing someone in the house for microphones is a dangerous thing.
Okay.
So, on this grid, there are those who approach God from coming to thinking and those who approach God from the feelings.
There are those who primarily conceive of God as imminent.
He's here.
He's concrete.
He's present.
And there are those who tend to gravitate toward that he's transcendent.
You know, our Father's here.
Who art in heaven there?
There are the transcendence of God, the omnipotence of God, the omnipotence of God.
And they're all right.
It's just why we prefer to approach God and conceive of God, because God is both imminent and he is transcendent.
We do approach God with God with God with our colleagues of thinking and they're both legitimate.
And last week, if you can recall, if you were here last week, Ryan did a textbook job, a message that focuses on the sinking and imminent God.
He walked us through the story of Jesus kneeling a blind man verse by verse.
And he walked us through verse by verse.
He helped us to understand the historical context in which this miracle, this storming is happening.
He helped us explore who Jesus' multi-faceted audience was.
Excuse me.
Jesus had actually several audiences.
And he even touched on, and I appreciate it, that John wrote this to an audience that was a generation away from the people that Jesus was talking to.
And remember, John tells us, and he recorded these things so that you, immediately, the people I'm writing to, a generation later, actually partially developed church by this point.
I'm writing to you, and so that's part of the story as well, as we unpack and as he left us, he gave us some clear, universal application of context.
Excellent.
Perfect.
It was very left-brain, which, again, wonderful.
We need it.
With this passage, Jesus actually is doing very right thing.
That's why he tells three stories with three different context, all around one scene, in a way that every one of them would have just made those immediate jumps.
They would have been there.
And he talked about the ghost people versus doing the door, versus the shepherd, and where the wolves get at, and where he used to speak.
He actually uses three different pictures that they would have been aware of, and they just listened to it.
And in fact, if you recall, in the first story, at the end, it says, they didn't understand the figure of speech.
By the way, when you keep trying to get to the right brain, when you try to speak to the right brain, what it means is you're not coming away with pure universal application.
But rather, you're trying to clear the context in which the Holy Spirit can speak to each person individually.
And what's your takeaway?
What's God trying to say to you?
It sounds like, also, someone will stand up in the meeting and say, well, you know, if you're not together, whenever I hear that, I'm like, uh-oh.
First of all, I think I really say that.
And about half the time, no, I didn't, but apparently the Spirit of God did.
And that's what they remembered, which I prefer.
You know, may I decrease, and may He increase.
So, today what I'd like to do is do some great, or less strange stuff.
I'll talk to the passage quickly.
And then, I want to actually kind of abandon the passage.
And rather than teach what Jesus taught, try to teach a little bit like Jesus taught.
When I was in my 20s, I had the privilege of sitting under Leighton Ford.
Leighton Ford was the vice president of Billy Graham Association.
He was one of the many speakers, a prolific author, a prolific speaker.
He also needed Billy's brother-in-law.
But his organization had this mantra, this kind of tagline.
Their goal was to lead more like Jesus that we might lead more to Jesus.
And so, for the second half, I want to try to step into a more right-brain approach and sort of do a left-brain, if you will allow me.
And my hope is that when we get into the right-brain, it's about images.
It's about a narrative.
It's about imagination.
It's about a creative mixing of things, which, by the way, Jesus takes a very, very common story and introduces a crazy idea that makes sense when you try to compare those two stories, but they couldn't even begin to think about.
Remember, God is their shepherd, and they know shepherds.
And shepherds will do what?
Well, shepherds will lay down their life for the feet.
They're willing to die for their feet because of the shepherd.
Look, it's the idea of a God who would die for me because I need it.
Whoa, what's that?
I mean, he blends these two pieces of the story, God as a shepherd and what a real shepherd is like, and brings them together in a way to introduce a critical piece of who he is as a good shepherd, but in a way that can't have a gift.
And it's a story.
The spirit of God needs to be loving to them.
And my hope is that when we're done, there may be some universal applications, but hopefully, particularly as we approach the table for communion, you ask God, what are the individual applications?
What are you saying, not to us, but what are you saying to me, God?
What's the truth for me?
Okay, can we go there?
Is that our thing?
If it's not real in any ways, but, you know, I sold that from Boston.
He does it all the time.
That's for missionary, as I was saying what you said.
Okay, so the first one, the good shepherd, the first story, the times it was first read before the first Song, is the sheep pen in town.
This is a communal sheep pen.
There are multiple settlers who all store their sheep in this communal sheep pen.
There is an actual gatekeeper of this sheep pen.
Each individual shepherd is not the gatekeeper, but there is an assigned gatekeeper for the communal sheep pen.
And Jesus is referring to this, and he actually talks about when the shepherd goes through the gatekeeper.
And interestingly, as Jesus starts this story, it's one of the clear places where he tells us very clearly who he's speaking to.
You can remember some of our previous messages that when we're trying to unpack what's used in your soul, we're talking about all these different audiences.
And they're all there here, but when he starts this first story, it's specific for us.
I read this.
Because he says, it's all Pharisees.
Listen to me.
Truly, I tell you Pharisees.
You know, Pharisees get a bad rap in the script.
First, they were trying to follow God.
Their only egos got caught up, as is often the case.
Many of them weren't still.
Some were good.
Nicodemus was an example of a really good Pharisee who was speaking God and trying.
Jews have actually tried to work with the gatekeepers.
Pharisees were gatekeepers.
They were the ones that let you know, the sheep in the county, when they were supposed to help.
And remember, when Jesus would heal someone, he would often say what?
Oh, go present yourself to the gatekeepers.
Go present yourself to the priest.
You know, often he'd even say, don't mention that I did it.
Just know what you're supposed to in the law.
So, Jesus was trying to work with the establishment that God had set up.
But when the establishment went sideways, he said, we're not going sideways.
This is where we're going.
And so, to the gatekeepers, to the Pharisees, who tells this first story.
It's a communicator.
There are, there's a gatekeeper.
And real shepherds, some of the town gatekeepers, thieves don't.
The thieves are known to be thieves, and they're going to go around the back side.
But now you know, one's a true shepherd.
Well, the gatekeepers don't recognize them.
But if the sheep, if the gatekeeper does recognize them, and opens up the gate anyways,
the sheep are not going to follow the liar, the face, because why?
They know his voice.
Now, I've been told, I've never observed this, but I've been told,
maybe even today in Israel, when you go to some of these communal pens,
and when they open them up, that several shepherds will just start walking in different directions
and give these calls.
And these calls, the sheep, are all normally, and within about three or four minutes,
as all the sheep get out, they all just start to go in the direction of their shepherds.
They hear the shepherd, they recognize the voice, and that's where they come.
That's the image that Jesus is portraying, that he's using.
He's telling, he's telling something that they know.
And when it's all done, it's there, if you're like,
yeah, we're not quite sure what he said.
We're not sure what he did.
And so, as is typical of Jesus, when they don't get it, he ranks it up a little bit.
He turns it up a little bit.
And then the second one is the sheep come out in the pasture.
So, often these shepherds would not bring their sheep back every night to town,
but they would stay out in the hinterlands.
And at night, they wanted their sheep all in one spot.
And so, they would do these, whoever gets there gets the sheep come.
And so, the shepherd, if it's smaller, it's less elaborate, there is no door.
And so, literally, the shepherd lays in front of the door.
He gets all the sheep in.
I'm cold.
The shepherd watches take his staff and hold it really low as he gets all the sheep to go in.
So, that as each sheep goes by, the sheep has to crawl under the staff.
And the staff pushes all the world back so that the shepherd can actually individually respect each sheep
to make sure that they're still doing okay.
Doesn't everyone feel like God has the ideal space?
And you're trying to move forward.
And it's really uncomfortable.
It's a nice community.
That's his promise.
That's true.
So, he gets more direct.
He doesn't call himself a shepherd at this point.
But when he says, I'm the boy,
they recognize that he's identifying as the shepherd.
And because they recognize the shepherd,
and the shepherd is also God,
and he's calling himself the shepherd,
emotions are starting to raise.
He's making some pretty bold statements.
But he's not going to turn up for you.
That's the beauty of the story.
Sometimes, it's why Jesus often talks in parables and in stories,
because they have this way of people getting underneath your defenses,
and they can't beat you.
Thank you, Jesus is telling the second story about this sheep thing out in the pasture,
where he used the door.
And he said, I need my sheep.
By the way, notice what he says.
I need my sheep.
So, when my children were all learning to drive,
we had 1990's Honda said it's five-speed.
And as I figured, if they couldn't learn to drive it on the five-speed,
well, then they weren't faced driving the five-speed.
They all begged me to take their test on the Toyota that was not automatic.
And I said, no.
And they said, why?
I said, because you're not going to drive this Toyota.
You're going to drive a Honda.
Well, we know that, but at least for the testing we drive this Toyota know.
Because if you can't pass the test in your stick,
then you're not good enough to drive this stick when I'm not allowed.
The other benefit, by the way, is it took them a year to get their license,
and you don't pay any insurance until they actually get their license.
So, there was a bit of a purpose.
But they drove that car so much that when Josiah, who was my firstborn,
about a year into it before Catherine got her learnings permit,
every now and then, Josiah said, hey, can I take my car?
And I'd say, sorry, you can take your car.
Where is it?
Because that was mine.
Where does Jesus, my feet,
he's already starting to identify with God.
He's making a dynamic line, but he's doing it by story.
And the way they say, get it.
And when I leave them, I'll leave them in.
And God, there is a thief, and that thief only wants to take.
I'm not like the thief that wants to take, but rather, I come that I might give.
And I come that I might give life, and it's not just give life, but give life abundantly.
By the way, this was my theme verse when I first met the Lord.
And I finally said yes to Jesus and gave up a bunch of garbage in my life.
The garbage is fun, but it was fun for a season.
And the same way is fun, it was fun for a season, and the next season ends, it's made us pretty ugly.
And so as I gave up all that garbage, I did it because Jesus said, I've come to give you life and that more abundantly.
And I thought I believed him, so I figured, okay, I'll take you up with me.
I want some of that life.
I want some of that abundance.
So Jesus is saying, this is the way I treat my sheep.
I give them abundant life.
Okay.
The third one, they're not in a pen at all.
And this is where Jesus says, I am the good shepherd.
And now in this case, he's making distinction between him and between a hireling.
Because for a hireling, when the sheep are all grazing, they're all over the place.
They're out in the field.
And there's many of them.
And it's much easier for a wolf to sneak up and stab one.
It's a little more dangerous.
It's a little less complaining.
If you're going to, if I'm going to take on a wolf, I'd rather have like a pen behind you
where you can't fit in and I've only got to deal with them here.
But if you're going to deal with the wolves out there, who knows how many wolves?
And how are you going to protest?
Jesus, I'm not right for a hireling.
Because if I may see the wolves, they get scared and they run.
Now, I'm the good shepherd.
I'm the good shepherd who stays by my sheep.
And what's it if he introduces the second man?
That he's the good shepherd who's going to lay down his life for the sheep.
I just love the way he does it.
Because in the one story of knowing what shepherds are like, that makes all the sense in the world.
And the other story of knowing what God's like is the good shepherd.
That makes no sense at all.
And therefore, emotionally, they try to wrestle with them.
This is the ultimate question, by the way.
Is he, the good shepherd, who lays down his life for your life, that he might give you life more abundantly?
And that you'll hear his voice, and you'll respond to his voice, and you'll follow.
This is the ultimate question of Christianity for us.
He is the shepherd.
Do we hear his voice and say yes to his leader?
And even when he's pushing us under this thing that looks like he's keeping us out, when he's really just expecting us.
Okay, so that's all your mystery stuff.
I'd like to just take the next 10, 15 minutes.
And rather than talk about the good shepherd, I'll talk about the good reason.
Okay.
You've also been on home steps.
In fact, I've been at some of your homes where you actually have, like, a ranch.
You have a house.
You have a well.
You have crops.
I think there are some animals here.
There's no animals left on them, because many of you have chickens, or I think some of you have sheep.
I wouldn't call you a shepherd, but you have sheep.
You have some other animals.
There are these, like, outprices which represent our gifts and our abilities.
There's fruit, things that's there.
I think, like any internal life, this is a picture of your own internal life that you need, you're called to care for as you walk with Jesus.
The house is your identity.
The well is where you receive sustenance.
You receive the living water of life, the word of God, the crops, feed you, the fruit trees are produced in your life.
Love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faith in the center, self-control against these.
There is nothing against them.
But we can just have them.
But let's be honest, in our own interior life, many of us have some weed patches.
And then we need to weed.
And I love the way the story puts the weed patches in the front, but all the way in the back is the snake pit.
That's the one that we all know is there.
We're trying to re-fight it.
We don't understand it.
We usually ignore it until one of the snakes get out and bite us.
And then we've got to go deal with snakes pit.
But what I think is most important about this, and it's the only one I'm going to explain a lot, because I'm not going to explain much, but notice the nice sense that goes around the homesick in your life.
So it's even good for us to have appropriate boundaries in our life.
And then there's a case where we let people into our inner life.
There are people who are welcome to come into my inner life, and they can go anywhere they want.
They can come almost any time, but there's very, very few of them.
Maybe there are more who are welcome into my gate when I invite them in.
Maybe they're an expert on my road.
Maybe they know how to weed better than I do and can help me.
Maybe my fruit trees look on the sticks, and I need them to come.
Maybe my snow spit, I'm finally willing to deal with it.
And as part of a community in our interior life, we maintain the fence of our life, we maintain the gate, but we allow people in because God desires that we nurture one another.
The word one another, I don't know, it's like a hundred and so many times in the scripting.
We want another, we want another, we want another.
And so this race is a picture of our interior life.
I'm going to show you some more with you.
And I'm not going to say a lot, but I'm going to pray before I show them, and just see if God's going to speak into your life and what you might need to do with them.
First of all, in the perfect world, we would learn healthy boundaries for our heritage.
In a good life, in a healthy life.
We would have learned many of the things.
Unfortunately, while friendless is done well,
the end result is unaccountable to you, but I'm responsible for me.
When you think about parenting, isn't this what parenting is all about?
You want to get your child to the place where they are accountable to me, but responsible for themselves.
Now, when they're one, they can't be responsible for themselves.
When they're two, they might be responsible enough to buckle their own seatbelts.
They're not responsible enough to cook their own dinner.
I don't know, maybe they can feed themselves.
My mom wouldn't let me feed myself if I ever do it without making a minute.
I'm sorry, dude, I saw her at age one a plate of spaghetti and said, how about it?
And about ten minutes in, there's spaghetti sauce all over his face, and here I'm like, okay, reach my grass up level.
I mean, enjoy, you know.
But she didn't mind.
She had a synchronicity over the sprayer and just take care of it afterwards.
But the goal is to train children to the place where they learn to be responsible for themselves, but accountable to others.
Unfortunately, many of us are only accountable to ourselves, and we want you to be responsible for it.
In fact, I would argue that almost all dysfunctional relationships are like them,
where we invoke unaccountable to me that you're responsible for them.
And so, in the world, we have imperfections, our heritage is flawed, and so we are unhealthy.
So, I just want to walk us through a couple simple pictures.
I want to use these three stories and see if you see yourself in any of it.
And as you do it, I want to start with a quote from Dallas Willard.
Dallas Willard said, you can do nothing without God.
But if you do nothing, it'll probably be without somebody.
But there is a part that we play in calling for our internal life.
God has to do it.
But we turn the cops.
We pull up the water.
We make sure the fence is good.
We open and close the gate based on his input into our life.
So, in the first place, I want to swallow it to fix the ranks.
This is the place where we conclude I can't possibly run this place.
Notice there's no gate broken down for us.
It seems that other people would become responsible for me.
It's done a instruction from others who weren't rescued by others.
But not at the level.
It gains friendships, gains marriages.
To love me with us.
This is the ranch that is where we'll build to seek.
Where we come to believe that we must give unlimited access in order to be loved.
Because we so want love that we'll take any thought out of it.
We'll do as you please.
It's lovely.
They may just stay out there.
People can so hurt that they conclude that people cannot be safe.
Change of corner is mistrust.
And there are some who actually give us a piece of thought.
They give us a piece of thought of you are welcome.
It gives you an impression of open, but never really lets you in.
And others who, although they still want to be loved, are so afraid of it that they push.
It's almost like, still love me now?
Still love me now?
We were made to be responsible for ourselves and accountable to one another.
This is the one that we often get in some of our more conservative churches.
The goal is controlled.
This is where one range that seems healthy, looks healthy, starts to annex other ranges.
You can't give advice, only directives.
Relationship is one of control and submission.
My own brokenness gets punted over with legalistic systems that I can try to follow.
And the only choice is the milk or rebel.
I can't tell you how many children I've seen leave.
Because that was their only choice.
And then the last thing, before we move to communion.
Another one's home.
This is the root of the weekly range.
Always about helping someone else.
I help someone else because I need to do it for me.
I get identity from it.
Maybe I had the LSU parent or the addicted parent and there was parental inversion
and I had to be the parent when I was only nine.
And so I've learned that the way you exist is by possibly being the parent with everyone.
And you're so busy out there helping and doing.
My first church, I had a guy, we were, we were, we bought two properties.
We raised one for the parking lot on.
The other one's going to be a parking lot.
It's going to be done in six weeks and I was going to move in.
Two years later, we were still working on it.
This one guy, he showed up all the time.
And he worked all kinds of hours to clean things out.
And every time he would start a project, it would grow.
He would remove one wall and he'd say, no, I removed the drywall, but now we need to do the electric wall.
And then we have to redo the plumbing.
And then we have to redo the fuses.
And then we have to move the wall.
And I thought he was a wonderful thing.
And about a year and a half ago, I realized he was just the inner way from home.
He didn't want to do all his own stuff.
No one was home.
By the way, if any of you are in counseling or if you're clergy, I mean, all the sessions are rampant with his fault.
Do the right things for the wrong reasons.
Okay.
I think if you're in our context today, you might say, I'm the big answer.
I'll help you fix the fences.
We can blame the moat or delegate.
I'll send people to help you if you will, or help you plant crops, or teach you how to weed.
People, and you can be accountable, but will allow you enough to never become responsible for you.
So if I did this well, how could you hate me and how could you like me?
If I knew you, people can come to their table.
I know if you can tell me.
You know, communion is this really unique ordinance that God has given us.
I like to use several loaves of bread.
I understand the individual cups.
They're both good at something that's unique.
Each person comes to communion as an individual that we ask to do this again.
But we partake collectively.
We are in a common union.
There is this reality of I remain responsible for me.
But I'm accountable to you.
That we are in this together.
That we partake of one life.
That there's one spirit.
That there's one subject.
And the good shepherd who loves you so much that I lay down my life for the sheep.
So the same as I have life, I'm going to have it abundantly.
As you come forward for communion, I'm going to say a word for you.
I'm going to bless the elements.
As you come forward, take the bread, take the cup, return to your fruit, and we'll partake of the bread together.
And we'll partake of the cup together.
Lord, Father, we thank you for this time.
Lord, it is well with my soul, though.
He does well.
You have time.
God, I tell you that in Jesus' name, you would send your spirit into the heart of each one of us.
We might ask for your help to be a good one to you.
Of the entire life that you have given us.
And the abundant life that you provide on the cross.
I thank you in Jesus' name.
Amen.
The outside will come.